Yoko Urano

yurano@princeton.edu

Research Interest

I am interested in understanding the aesthetic experience through quantitative measures. Specifically, I am interested in what variables in a design contribute to impressions of beauty, cultural variations in aesthetic preferences, and more fundamental topics concerning what structures and circuits in the brain allow humans to experience a visual stimulus as "aesthetically pleasing".

Research Experience

Research Assistant Tsukuba University Al Lab

November 2020 - August 2021

The Al lab is led by Dr. Kenji Suzuki and focuses on cybernics and social interaction engineering.

- Designed a new user interface for an app to be used with HugBits, a haptic communication device developed by the lab.
- Designed and ran a usability test for the overall HugBits system.

Undergraduate Research Assistant, TLAB

September 2019 - May 2020

TLAB (social perception lab) is led by Dr. Alexander Todorov. The lab focuses on high level perceptual phenomena; e.g., impression formation, aesthetics.

- Regular attendance and contribution to weekly lab meetings.
- Collecting and analyzing data for my research on visual hierarchy.

ReMatch+ Program

June 2019 – August 2019

ReMatch+ is a summer program that pairs undergraduates with graduate students to conduct research

- Worked with Aaron Kurosu (Ph.D. candidate) to explore a graphic design principle known as "visual hierarchy."
- Found empirical evidence that people will look at graphic design similarly when they find it designed well.

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology Princeton University
Certificate, Visual Arts Princeton University
Diploma Shibuya Kyoiku Gakuen Shibuya Senior High School

Expected May 2023 Expected May 2023 March 2018

Professional & Academic Experience

Social Chair Club Ultimate Frisbee

November 2021 – Present

Organized and executed team bonding events.

Treasurer Japanese Students Association

September 2021 – Present

Maintained budget and wrote funding applications for events.

Y. Urano: 1 of 3

Designer The Unmasked Project

November 2020 - Present

The Unmasked Project is a student-built app that provides a supportive, anonymous community for college students and aims to facilitate conversations about mental health.

- Designed a rebranding of social media
- Designed marketing materials, including GIFs, flyers, and email templates

Intern TELL Japan

September 2020 - January 2021

TELL is an NPO that provides mental health services and education to the international community in Japan.

- Designed flyers and social media graphics for events
- Maintained the TELL Twitter account
- Gathered and organized updated information about healthcare in Japan for the TELL website
- Analyzed Facebook engagement data and identified key predictors for engagement
- Recorded and edited a guided meditation for publication on TELL's social media

Graphic Designer Student Design Agency

October 2018 - May 2020

Designed posters, logos, etc. for on-campus organizations and departments.

Publicity Chair Club Ultimate Frisbee

June 2019 – May 2020

Designed promotional material and maintained social media.

Social Chair Japanese Students Association

January 2019 - May 2020

Planned and organized social events.

Graphic Designer Princeton University Science Olympiad September 2019 – February 2020 Designed promotional material and social media graphics.

Poster Presentations

Visual Hierarchy Relates to Impressions of Good Design

September 2021

International Association of Empirical Aesthetics Conference

Visual Hierarchy Relates to Impressions of Good Design

May 2021

CHI Workshop "Eye Movements as an Interface to Cognitive State"

Good Visual Hierarchy is Good Design

August 2019

ReMatch+

Distinctions

Scholar Yanai Tadashi Foundation

December 2017 - Present

The Yanai Tadashi Foundation International Scholarship Program provides financial support to Japanese students in their studies at overseas universities.

Student Judge Princeton Research Day

May 2019

Princeton Research Day is an annual event that showcases student research at Princeton.

German Book Prize German Department, Princeton University

April 2019

The Book Prize is awarded to students in recognition of achievement in the study of German.

Languages

Lariguag

English fluent
Japanese fluent
German conversational
R intermediate
JavaScript intermediate
HTML intermediate
CSS intermediate
Python beginner

Software

Adobe Illustrator intermediate
Adobe InDesign intermediate
Adobe AfterEffects intermediate
Adobe Dimension beginner
Blender intermediate